crisisgroup.org 2019-04-18

# Privacy Policy | Crisis Group

This statement comprises the privacy policy (the **“Policy”** ) of the International Crisis Group ( **“Crisis Group”/“we”/“us”/“our”** ) as it pertains to our website ( **“Website”** ). This Policy does not cover Crisis Group’s presence on social media platforms such as, including but not limited to: Youtube, Facebook, Google+, Linkedin, Twitter, Tumblr, Pinterest, Flickr, Soundcloud, and on publishing platforms such as, including but not limited to: Issuu, Scribd, Medium on which we have established our own presence. In the context of those platforms, we are merely another user and the privacy policies as well as the terms and conditions of those platforms are applicable.

This Policy sets out the basis on which any information that personally identifies you or enables us to contact you ( **“Personal Information”** ) that we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your Personal Information and how we will treat it. If you feel that we are not abiding by this Policy, you should immediately [contact our Online Editor](mailto:aolafs@crisisgroup.org) and we will try to resolve your concerns.

We welcome you to use our Website, which can be accessed and browsed without the need to submit any contact details or other Personal Information.

  1. **Collection of Information**  
 
    1. We may collect and process your Personal Information that you provide in the following ways:  
 
      * **Contacting Crisis Group:** If you choose to contact us through the Website for any reason, we will collect the information you voluntarily provide to us.  We use a third party platform, Recruitee, to manage the information submitted by you when you apply for career opportunities with Crisis Group. Any information you submit through the form on our Career Opportunities page is provided by you to Recruitee and is also subject to Recruitee’s [privacy policy](https://recruitee.com/privacy). We have the right to access such Personal Information and process the Personal Information for the purposes as set out below.  
 
      * **Signing up for our email newsletters:** We use a third party platform, Mailchimp, to manage our email distribution lists. If you choose to register for our email newsletters by clicking “Register” on our Website, you will be presented with a secured form in which you will be asked to provide your Personal Information, which includes your email address, and you will be asked to select your mailing preferences. Any information you submit through this secured form is provided directly by you to Mailchimp and is also subject to Mailchimp’s [privacy policy](http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). We have a data processing agreement in place with Mailchimp, as we are the controller of such Personal Information provided by you to Mailchimp and as we have the right to access such Personal Information and process the Personal Information for the purposes as set out below.  
 
      * **Making a donation:** We use a third party, Stripe, to process online donations to Crisis Group made electronically through our Website. If you choose to make a donation by clicking “Support Crisis Group”, you will be transferred to Stripe’s secured form. Any information you submit via our Website through Stripe’s secured donations form is provided directly by you to Stripe and is subject to Stripe’s [privacy policy](https://stripe.com/be/privacy). Stripe will provide us with certain information about you (including your name, billing address, email address, donation amount, whether the donation is made in honour of someone, and the reason for the donation if applicable, but not your credit card number) when you choose to make an online donation to Crisis Group through the Website.   
 
      * **Offline submissions:** We may also collect information provided by you offline (e.g., through written correspondence you to send to us or when you provide us with your business card).  
 
    2. We may automatically collect the following information with regard to each of your visits to the Website: 
      * Technical information, including the operating system and platform, browser type and version; and  
 
      * Details of your visits to the Website, including but not limited to: every ‘HTTP Query’ your browser client sent to our server(s); the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from the Website (including date and time); page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data. This information does not identify you.

  2. **Use of information**  
 
    1. Your Personal Information may be used in the following ways:  
 
      * If you have signed up to receive email updates, etc. via the registration form on our Website, your Personal Information will be used by us to send you via MailChimp the requested publications and to send you occasional emails advising you of Crisis Group updates or requesting donations.  
 
      * If you have contacted us via the contact details provided on our Website, we will use the information you have provided, including your name and email address, to respond to your inquiry.  
 
      * Any Personal Information you submit when applying for career opportunities will be used solely for recruitment purposes (including for identifying job applicants, evaluating applications, making hiring and employment decisions, and contacting you by phone or in writing).  
 
      * Any Personal Information you submit when making a donation through the “Donations” section of the Website will be used by Stripe to process your transaction. Stripe will provide us with certain personal information about you (including your name, billing address, email address, donation amount, whether the donation is made in honour of someone, and the reason for the donation if applicable, but not your credit card number) when you choose to make an online donation, and we will use this information to produce and send to you an acknowledgement letter and for our internal records. Please note that if you make a donation anonymously, Stripe will still share your name and other Personal Information with us for our own internal records - we will not include your name in our publications.  
 
      * Any information you provide to us offline will only be used for the purpose for which you have provided it, e.g., if you provide us with your business card and request that we send you information.  
 
    2. Your information may also be used for technical purposes, including:  
 
      * To ensure that content from the Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; and  
 
      * statistical purposes.  
 
  3. **Disclosure of information**  
 
    1. We will never share your Personal Information with any other company or third party without your consent, except in the following circumstances (each as permitted by applicable law, in particular, with regard to a transfer out of the EEA, as applicable):  
 
      * as set out in this Policy;  
 
      * when we are required to do so by law, for example, in response to a subpoena, in response to a court order or other legal obligation, or in response to a valid request from a law enforcement agency;  
 
      * to protect the security or confidentiality of our records and systems;  
 
      * in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with our rights, or  
 
      * in the event that we sell or transfer all, or any portion of, our business or assets (including in the event of any reorganisation, dissolution, spin-off, or liquidation) we reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information to the relevant acquirer, successor, purchaser or beneficiary, or any appropriate combination of them.  
 
  4. **International data transfers**  
 
    1. We operate globally and may have a need to transfer certain Personal Information to countries outside the EEA which do not provide an adequate level as required under EU data protection law. We use Standard Contractual Clauses to ensure that your Personal Information is adequately protected and your privacy respected in the case of such a transfer.  
 
    2. When you sign up for email updates, MailChimp may transfer, process and store your Personal Information outside the EEA in line with its privacy policy.  
 
    3. When you make a donation, Stripe may transfer, process and store your Personal Information outside the EEA in line with its privacy policy. Please see section 7 below for more information.  
 
  5. **Cookies**  
 
    1. Like most websites, our Website may place a “cookie” – a small text file – in the browser of your computer.  This cookie will assign you a unique number that allows us to save your information so that the information does not need to be re-entered.  Cookies can be either “persistent” or “session” based.  Our Website uses both types of cookies.  
 
    2. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer, contain an expiration date (by default the cookies expire after 23 days), and may be used to track your browsing behaviour upon return to the issuing website or component (such as plugins or embedded media, e.g., a YouTube video embedded on our website).  You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your internet browser’s “Help” menu.  
 
    3. Session cookies are short-lived, are used only during a browsing session, and expire when you quit your browser.  
 
    4. You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. Instructions on how to do so will vary from browser to browser but you can find out more at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). Some features and functionality may be lost if you choose to disable cookies.  Also, remember that you will have to adjust the cookie settings for each browser and device and you use to visit our Website.  
 
    5. Our Website may contain links to other sites that may use cookie technology. We do not have access to, or control over, these cookies.  
 
  6. **Security**  
 
    1. We use reasonable precautions to protect your Personal Information and to store it securely.  Our Website has a secure SSL certificate, a global standard security technology that enables encrypted communication between the web browser and the web server.  
 
    2. If you choose to make an electronic donation to Crisis Group, you will be transferred to Stripe’s secured form, where the donation process will be completed.  Please refer to section 1.1 above for further information concerning the electronic donations process.   
 
    3. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. We will do our best to protect your Personal Information, but cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our Website; any transmission is at your own risk.  
 
  7. **Storage and accuracy of information**  
 
    1. The accuracy of your Personal Information is important to us. If you change your email address or would like to change your email preferences,  you may do so by clicking “update your preferences” at the bottom of each of our email updates to which you have subscribed.  
 
    2. The Personal Information you provide when applying for career opportunities on our Website is stored by Recruitee in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://recruitee.com/privacy).  
 
    3. The Personal Information you provide when signing up for our email updates is stored on Mailchimp’s servers in the United States.  
 
    4. The Personal Information you provide when making a donation via Stripe is stored on the servers of Stripe and Stripe’s third party hosting providers that are located in Belgium, Ireland and the United States. Our development team also stores the Personal Information of our donors on a third party platform, Raiser’s Edge, and is also subject to their [privacy policy](https://www.blackbaud.co.uk/privacy-policy.aspx).  
 
    5. All other Personal Information that you provide to us is stored on our server in Belgium and kept in a reasonably secure environment. We will only store your Personal Information in our systems for as long as is necessary.  
 
  8. **Direct marketing**  
 
    1. We do not share your Personal Information with third parties without your consent except in the limited circumstances set out in section 3 above.  
 
    2. If you have provided your email address to receive email updates, you may also receive occasional requests for donations as indicated in our registration form. If you have made a donation, you will receive a link in your donation receipt enabling you to sign up for our email updates. In these communications, however, you will be given the opportunity to opt out of receiving such emails by clicking on the link provided in the email. Please note that if you opt out of the occasional emails requesting donations, you will unsubscribe from all of our mailing lists.  
 
  9. **Access to Personal Information**  
 
    1. You have the right to access your Personal Information that we hold. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with applicable privacy legislation.  
 
    2. You may request at any time a copy of the information we hold on you by sending an e-mail to our [Online Editor](mailto:aolafs@crisisgroup.org). Any access request may be subject to a fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information that we hold about you.  
 
  10. **Changes to our Policy**  
 
    1. Our Policy may change in the future. We encourage you to review this page periodically to understand our Policy regarding our collection and use of your Personal Information.  The date of this Policy, as stated below, indicates the last time this Policy was materially revised (the “ **Effective Date** ”).  Checking the Effective Date below allows you to determine whether there have been changes since the last time you reviewed this Policy.  
 
  11. **Contact**  
 
    1. Questions, comments and requests regarding this Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to our [Online Editor](mailto:aolafs@crisisgroup.org).

**Effective Date of Privacy Policy:** August 2016
